More merciless. More shameless.
Scary Movie 2 is a comedy film directed by Keenen Ivory Wayans.
While the original parodied slasher flicks like Scream, Keenen Ivory Wayans's
sequel to Scary Movie takes comedic aim at haunted house movies.
A group of students visit a mansion called "Hell
House," and murderous high jinks ensue.
Cindy Campbell, played by Anna Faris.
Buddy Wilkerson, played by Christopher Masterson.
Brenda Meeks, played by Regina Hall.
Ray Wilkins, played by Shawn Wayans.
Shorty Meeks, played by Marlon Wayans.
Dwight Hartman, played by David Cross.
Scary Movie 2 is a 2001 American supernatural parody
film directed by Keenen Ivory Wayans.
It is a sequel to Scary Movie and the second
installment in the Scary Movie film series.
The film stars Anna Faris, Regina Hall, Shawn Wayans, and Marlon Wayans (all reprising their roles from the first film, despite their characters having
been killed), as well as Tim Curry, Tori Spelling, Chris Elliott, Chris Masterson, Kathleen Robertson, David Cross, and James Woods.
The film was the last in the series to feature the involvement of stars Marlon and
Shawn Wayans, and director Keenen until the upcoming sixth installment.
Where the original film was mainly based on the slasher films of the 1990s, Scary Movie 2 parodies an array of supernatural and haunted house films from various decades, namely The Haunting (1999), Stigmata (1999), The Exorcist (1973), The Rocky Horror Picture
Show (1975), The Amityville Horror (1979), Poltergeist (1982), The Legend of Hell House (1973), House on Haunted Hill (both the 1959 and 1999 versions), The Changeling (1980), What Lies Beneath (2000), and Bloodbath at the House of Death (1984).
It also spoofs the comedy film Dude, Where's My Car?
(2000) and some contemporary films, such as Hannibal (2001),
Hollow Man (2000), and Charlie's Angels (2000).
Scary Movie 2 grossed $141 million worldwide and received
largely negative reviews from critics.
A sequel, Scary Movie 3, was released in 2003.
The film explores themes of exorcism, haunted
house, parody, spoof, horror spoof.
The tone is lighthearted.